<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-10-03T11:46:17+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Water, Vegetation, &amp;amp; Society</title><subtitle>Understanding the coupled dynamics of water, vegetation and ecosystem services in drylands.</subtitle><author><name>Kelly Caylor</name><email>caylor@ucsb.edu</email></author><entry><title type="html">Monitoring crop production and farmer decision-making in central Kenya</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/10/03/Kenya-wsc-2018-activities/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Monitoring crop production and farmer decision-making in central Kenya" /><published>2018-10-03T03:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-10-03T03:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/10/03/Kenya-wsc-2018-activities</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/10/03/Kenya-wsc-2018-activities/">&lt;p&gt;Imagine you are a smallholder farmer in Kenya who relies on rainfall and mountain-fed irrigation for your agriculture. After experiencing &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.chg.ucsb.edu/?p=266&quot;&gt;back-to-back&lt;/a&gt; droughts in 2016 and 2017, you are unsure about what to expect for the upcoming 2018 growing season. Will the rains come back this year? Will there be yet another drought? These questions affect important decisions that farmers make before and during the growing season such as whether to plant drought-resistent crops or whether to purchase early maturing seed varieties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2018 rainy season in central Kenya has been anything but ordinary. While many farmers relished the above-average volumes of rainfall which they hope will lead to a productive growing season, other farmers suffered from the deluges that led to flooded fields and washed away crops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The WAVES team, led by PhD student &lt;a href=&quot;/people/krell/&quot;&gt;Natasha Krell&lt;/a&gt;, sought out to understand these questions surrounding agricultural decision-making using advances in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nsf.gov/news/mmg/mmg_disp.jsp?med_id=82037&amp;amp;from=&quot;&gt;real-time crop monitoring weather stations&lt;/a&gt; and social science surveys. Together with our instrumental Kenya-based team members, &lt;a href=&quot;/people/gitonga/&quot;&gt;John Gitonga&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/people/mukoma/&quot;&gt;Boniface Mukoma&lt;/a&gt;, the WAVES lab deployed ca. 60 field-based Arable Mark crop-monitoring weather stations as well as led social science surveys of over 600 farmers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/kenya-arable-install-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research collaborations between the WAVES lab at U.C. Santa Barbara, the University of Arizona, the California Polytechnic State University, and the Mpala Research Center in Laikipia, Kenya
culminated in a household survey on agricultural management, water resource governance, use of weather and climate forecasts, coping and adaptation to climate as well as other topics. The researchers gathered longitudinal data on over 600 heads of households or spouses in Laikipia, Meru and Nyeri counties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the NSF-WSC grant comes to an end in 2019, our research highlights advances in environmental data collection through a field-based sensor network along with farmer surveys to better understand how smallholders respond to climate variability. Our findings can provide insight on agricultural shocks such as crop failure or pest and disease occurence, and to what extent these shocks can be predicted and mitigated.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Natasha Krell</name><email>nkrell@ucsb.edu</email></author><category term="Smallholder Agriculture" /><category term="Kenya" /><category term="Fieldwork" /><category term="Water Sustainability Climate" /><category term="Mpala Research Center" /><category term="Natasha Krell" /><category term="2018" /><summary type="html">NSF WSC grant culminates in deployment of ca. 60 Arable Marks and social surveys involving several universities in Kenya's Mount Kenya region</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ryan Avery developing ML system for Omidyar Network at Clark Labs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/06/29/summer-omidyar-project/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ryan Avery developing ML system for Omidyar Network at Clark Labs" /><published>2018-06-29T03:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-06-29T03:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/06/29/avery-summer-omidyar</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/06/29/summer-omidyar-project/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/people/avery/&quot;&gt;Ryan Avery&lt;/a&gt; will be at Clark Labs developing software for the project “Developing and Scaling Up The Mapping Africa Active Learning Platform”, funded by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.omidyar.com/insights/reimagining-agricultural-insurance-protect-smallholder-farmers-worldwide&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Omidyar Network&lt;/a&gt;. He will be working with the team to build a scalable system for detecting smallholder farm fields across Africa, focusing first on a sub-region of Ghana. Crowdsourced maps of smallholder fields have been shown to be an effective data source to train models to predict the locations of unmapped fields. Ryan work this summer will be to implement neural network and random forest models on Amazon Web Service’s cloud computing infrastructure to locate fields with near human-level ability at flexible spatial scale. Ultimately the deliverable sof this project will be a rich dataset of smallholder agriculture locations across Africa, opening new possibilities for targeted research on changing land use patterns and land cover in dynamic agricultural regions. The methods work is a continuation of &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rse.2016.03.010&quot;&gt;Debats et al. 2016&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rse.2016.03.010&quot;&gt;Debats et al. 2017&lt;/a&gt;. He will return to UCSB in mid-September to start his second year, and will continue to collaborate with the project team remotely.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ryan Avery</name><email>ravery@ucsb.edu</email></author><category term="Smallholder Agriculture" /><category term="Ghana" /><category term="Remote Sensing" /><category term="Deep Learning" /><category term="Ryan Avery" /><summary type="html">Ryan is working as a Researcher at Clark Labs to develop the scalable machine learning component of an active learning system to detect smallholder agriculture</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">WAVES Lab Postdoctoral Positions Available</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/05/10/postdocs_2018/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WAVES Lab Postdoctoral Positions Available" /><published>2018-05-10T19:01:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-05-10T19:01:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/05/10/postdocs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/05/10/postdocs_2018/">&lt;p&gt;Two research (Associate Specialist) positions are available within the Water, Vegetation, and Society Lab (WAVES) at the Earth Research Institute at the University of California, Santa Barbara.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;riparian-ecohydrological-dynamics&quot;&gt;Riparian Ecohydrological Dynamics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first position is in the area of riparian ecohydrological dynamics. The WAVES lab (&lt;a href=&quot;http://caylor.eri.ucsb.edu&quot;&gt;caylor.eri.ucsb.edu&lt;/a&gt;) is participating in two multi-institutional projects that seek to develop novel insight into the the sustainability and resilience of riparian forest ecosystems and tools for quantitative support of land/water conservation management plans in arid and semi-arid landscapes across the southwestern US and southern France. Our project goals are to detect and assess the responses of sensitive riparian forests to drought stress over recent decades, and to generalize these responses through modeling of a warming/drying climate punctuated by variable rainfall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A successful candidate’s duties would include, under supervision and within a multi-institution team environment: (1) developing and implementing landscape-scale models of riparian ecohydrology that incorporate stochastic dynamics of rainfall, surface/subsurface dynamics, plant water use and vegetation stress; (2) integrating and verifying model dynamics against multi-year meteorological data and isotopic records of riparian vegetation water sources; (3) leveraging high-resolution imagery of vegetation function and structure derived from unmanned autonomous vehicles for improved characterization of riparian ecohydrological dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additional detail regarding this research effort can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://caylor.eri.ucsb.edu/2018/01/28/riparian-ecohydrology-awards/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Interested individuals can appy &lt;a href=&quot;https://recruit.ap.ucsb.edu/apply/JPF01253&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;coupled-natural-human-system-modeling&quot;&gt;Coupled Natural-Human System Modeling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second position is in the area of coupled natural-human system modeling. The WAVES lab (caylor.eri.ucsb.edu) is conducting research that seeks to reveal the dynamics of production and consumption of food, energy, and water resources in sub-Saharan Africa, and use these revelations to develop solutions that can better sustain coupled food, energy, and water systems through improved multi-scale, multi-resource governance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A successful candidate’s duties would include, under supervision and within a multi-institution team environment: (1) developing and implementing models of coupled natural-human systems within smallholder agricultural settings; (2) integrating and verifying model dynamics against novel data sets of high-frequency, co-located in-situ observations of agricultural decision making and crop/climate dynamics; (3) leading the authorship of research manuscripts for publication based on model development and applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additional detail regarding this research effort can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smallholder.ag&quot;&gt;www.smallholder.ag&lt;/a&gt;. Interested individuals can apply &lt;a href=&quot;https://recruit.ap.ucsb.edu/apply/JPF01252&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kelly Caylor</name></author><category term="2018" /><category term="Postdoctoral Researchers" /><category term="Water Sustainability and Climate" /><category term="NSF" /><category term="Riparian Ecohydorology" /><category term="SERDP" /><summary type="html">The WAVES Lab has two postdoctoral research associate positions available starting in the fall of 2018.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IFPRI Researcher, Dr. Kwaw Andam, Visits WAVES Lab</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/04/07/ifpri-waves/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IFPRI Researcher, Dr. Kwaw Andam, Visits WAVES Lab" /><published>2018-04-07T19:01:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-04-07T19:01:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/04/07/kwaw-waves</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/04/07/ifpri-waves/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Kwaw_UCSB.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kwaw Photo&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ifpri.org/profile/kwaw-andam&quot;&gt;Dr. Kwaw Andam&lt;/a&gt;, a research fellow at the International Food Policy Research Institutes’s (IFPRI) Ghana Strategy Support Program recently visited the WAVES lab and the Department of Geography at UCSB for a week of collaboration. Previously an economist for the World Bank, Dr. Andam’s research focuses on agro-processing, value chain analysis, and livestock production in Ghana. He and &lt;a href=&quot;/people/tuholske/&quot;&gt;Cascade Tuholske&lt;/a&gt; conducted an urban food security survey in Accra in summer 2017 to assess the demographic, socioeconomic, and spatial predictors of household food security in low- and middle-income neighborhoods in Accra, Ghana’s capital. This research is supported by a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.purdue.edu/discoverypark/food/programs/borlaug-fellows/graduate-research-grants.php&quot;&gt;Borlaug Fellowship in Global Food Security&lt;/a&gt; and IFPRI. While at UCSB, Dr. Andam assisted Cascade with data analysis and drafting of a paper that they plan to publish this spring. While much of his time was spent in the office, Dr. Andam still had time to visit local favorites such as Cold Springs Tavern and the Santa Barbara Harbor.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Cascade Tuholske</name><email>cascade@umail.ucsb.edu</email><uri>https://www.tuholske.com</uri></author><category term="2018" /><category term="IFPRI" /><category term="Cascade Tuholske" /><category term="Food Security" /><summary type="html">Dr. Kwaw Andam, a research fellow at the International Food Policy Research Institutes's Ghana Strategy Support Program in Accra visited our lab at UCSB to collaborate on an urban food security research project.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">WAVES Lab Recieves Funding for Riparian Ecohydrology Projects</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/28/riparian-ecohydrology-awards/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WAVES Lab Recieves Funding for Riparian Ecohydrology Projects" /><published>2018-01-27T03:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-01-27T03:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/28/funding-new-awards-for-riparian-ecohydrology</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/28/riparian-ecohydrology-awards/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/TuolumneRiver.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tuolumne River riparian corridor&quot; class=&quot;align-left&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re excited about two new projects that are starting in 2018. The first is an NSF project funded through the Geo Directorate, &lt;a href=&quot;https://nsf.gov/awardsearch/showAward?AWD_ID=1700555&quot;&gt;“Collaborative Research: Impacts of Dynamic, Climate-Driven Water Availability on Tree Water Use and Health in Mediterranean Riparian Forests”&lt;/a&gt;. This project - a collaboration between WAVES lab, &lt;a href=&quot;https://people.eri.ucsb.edu/~bliss/&quot;&gt;Michael Singer&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.esf.edu/faculty/stella/&quot;&gt;John Stella&lt;/a&gt; - aims to build new understanding of the ecohydrological links between water availability and forest health by employing an interdisciplinary set of research methods. Over the coming three years, our team will combine: 1) field-based measurements of climate and hydrology and laboratory analysis of oxygen isotopes from all potential tree water sources; (2) contemporary and retrospective analysis of oxygen and carbon isotopes in annual tree-rings to investigate recent climate-driven fluctuations in tree water use and water use efficiency; (3) seasonal (intra-annual) analysis of oxygen isotopes via high-resolution “micro-slicing” of annual tree rings to assess seasonal fluctuations in tree water source use; and 4) improvement and application of a climate-driven numerical ecohydrology model that includes dynamic water fluxes into the floodplain, isotopic fractionation/mixing, and tree water uptake. It will compare the ecohydrologic responses to climate in water availability at forest sites along a strong climatic gradient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second project is being funded by the Department of Defense’s “Strategic Environmental Research and Development Program” (SERDP). Our proposal, “Understanding and Assessing Riparian Habitat Vulnerability to Drought-prone Climate Regimes on Department of Defense Bases in the Southwestern USA”, will provide a toolkit and quantitative support for land/water conservation management plans that promote the sustainability and resilience of riparian forest ecosystems in arid and semi-arid landscapes. The four-year project, also led by Michael Singer, is a collaboration between WAVES Lab, John Stella, and Dar Roberts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two awards were &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.news.ucsb.edu/2018/018656/champions-forests&quot;&gt;recently featured&lt;/a&gt; in the UCSB Current.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kelly Caylor</name></author><category term="Kelly Caylor" /><category term="California" /><category term="NSF" /><category term="SERDP" /><category term="Department of Defense" /><category term="Conservation Science" /><category term="Riparian Ecohydrology" /><category term="Isotope Hydrology" /><summary type="html">The WAVES lab is part of two newly-funded projects focused on climate change and conservation of riparian forests in mediterranean drylands. The projects are led by Michael Singer, and also involve collaborators Dar Roberts At UCSB and John Stella at SUNY-ESF.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">WAVES Lab Contributes to 2017 FAO State of Food &amp;amp; Agriculture Report</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/06/02/cascade-fao/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WAVES Lab Contributes to 2017 FAO State of Food &amp; Agriculture Report" /><published>2017-10-10T19:01:00+03:00</published><updated>2017-10-10T19:01:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/06/02/casade-fao</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/06/02/cascade-fao/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/FAO_HQ_Rome.png&quot; alt=&quot;Fullbright Badge&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO) released its flagship report &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/state-of-food-agriculture/en/&quot;&gt;2017 The State of Food and Agriculture: Leveraging Food Systems for Inclusive Rural Transformation&lt;/a&gt; last week. Focused on strengthening rural livelihoods through rural-urban linkages, the report outlines the challenges and opportunities for food systems in rapidly urbanizing low- and lower-middle-income countries. &lt;a href=&quot;/people/tuholske/&quot;&gt;Cascade Tuholske&lt;/a&gt;, WAVES lab member and PhD student in Geography at UCSB, had the fortune to contribute to sections on urbanization and urban food systems. Rural communities may benefit from urbanization as urban consumer demand for food increases. However, urbanization can also lead to neglect of rural communities. To capitalize on urbanization to grow rural economies, the report encourages policymakers to develop inclusive and integrative strategies that specifically link rural economies and food systems with neighboring small towns and cities. Through such policies, countries can work toward achieving &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/sustainable-development-goals/goals/goal-2/en/&quot;&gt;zero hunger&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/sustainable-development-goals/goals/goal-1/en/&quot;&gt;zero poverty&lt;/a&gt; by 2030.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Cascade Tuholske</name><email>cascade@umail.ucsb.edu</email><uri>https://www.tuholske.com</uri></author><category term="2017" /><category term="FAO" /><category term="Cascade Tuholske" /><category term="Food Security" /><summary type="html">Cascade Tuholske contributed to urbanization and urban food security sections in FAO's 2017 State of Food and Agriculture Report.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Arable Mark deployments in Zambia’s Southern Province</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/27/Zambia-arable-marks-2017/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Arable Mark deployments in Zambia’s Southern Province" /><published>2017-09-27T03:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2017-09-27T03:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/27/Zambia-arable-marks-2017</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/27/Zambia-arable-marks-2017/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/allan-arable-summer17.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;align-right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WAVES lab members &lt;a href=&quot;/people/caylor/&quot;&gt;Kelly&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/people/krell/&quot;&gt;Natasha&lt;/a&gt; teamed up with Arable Labs and Zambia’s Agricultural Research Institute to install close to 60 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nsf.gov/news/mmg/mmg_disp.jsp?med_id=82037&amp;amp;from= &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;  Internet of Things devices &lt;/a&gt; in the southern province of Zambia. Supported by a National Science Foundation Water Sustainability and Climate grant, this research seeks to understand climate variability impacts on smallholder agriculture in Zambia and Kenya. By coupling social information collected via SMS and environmental monitoring and measuring via low-cost solar-powered environmental sensors, we can better understand intraseasonal farmer decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arable Labs recently highlighted our work on their &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ArableLabs/how-4m-in-nsf-funded-work-fills-data-gap-to-improve-farmers-climate-adaptation-9553efc37859&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; blog. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Natasha Krell</name><email>nkrell@ucsb.edu</email></author><category term="2017" /><category term="Zambia" /><category term="Natasha Krell" /><category term="Food Security" /><category term="Water Sustainability Climate" /><category term="ZARI" /><summary type="html">Water Sustainability Climate work wraps up with close to 60 Arable Marks deployed in Zambia's southern province.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">WAVES Lab researchers participate in Kenyan National Science Week Exhibition</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/20/National-Science-Week/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WAVES Lab researchers participate in Kenyan National Science Week Exhibition" /><published>2017-09-20T13:49:05+03:00</published><updated>2017-09-20T13:49:05+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/20/WAVES-at-kenyan-national-science-week</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/20/National-Science-Week/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/index_125_2848007035.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WAVES at Mpala&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kenya’s National Science Week, organized by NACOSTI, aims to showcase achievements in science and technology in Kenya and provide a forum for scientists and stakeholders to interact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two WAVES Lab members -  Charles Gitonga and Moses Kioko - were on hand to explain WAVES Lab research findings that have implications for smallholder agriculture, food security and rangeland management to visitors. Charles and Moses represented the Mpala Research Center in this weeklong event (May 22-26, 2017) for the second time this year. At the Mpala booth, they displayed informational materials (from Mpala’s latest Mpala Memos newsletter and brochure to Rangeland Monitoring Guides and short documentaries) and featured poster presentations by students and researchers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through the event, Charles and Moses connected with a wide variety of researchers and non-scientists, sparking interest in collaborations and increasing public awareness of our research, outreach and conservation efforts.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kelly Caylor</name></author><category term="Mpala" /><category term="Kenya" /><category term="Water Sustainability and Climate" /><category term="Kenya" /><category term="Outreach" /><summary type="html">WAVES Lab researchers working at the Mpala Research Center in Kenya were participants in the 6th Annual National Science Week Exhibition at the KICC, in Nairobi.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cascade Tuholske awarded Borlaug Fellowship to research urban food security in Ghana &amp;amp; Zambia</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/06/02/cascade-borlaug/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cascade Tuholske awarded Borlaug Fellowship to research urban food security in Ghana &amp; Zambia" /><published>2017-06-04T19:01:00+03:00</published><updated>2017-06-04T19:01:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/06/02/casade-borlaug</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/06/02/cascade-borlaug/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Cascade_borlaug.png&quot; alt=&quot;Fullbright Badge&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/people/tuholske/&quot;&gt;Cascade Tuholske&lt;/a&gt;, WAVES lab member and PhD student in Geography at UCSB, was named a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.purdue.edu/discoverypark/food/borlaugfellows/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; Borlaug Fellow in Global Food Security &lt;/a&gt; to examine urban food security in Accra, Ghana and Lusaka, Zambia. With Sub-Saharan Africa becoming increasingly urban, Cascade’s research aims to uncover the underlying processes and determinants of household food security within African cities. In partnership with the International Food Policy Research Institute, he will lead a team of local enumerators to survey households in Accra to understand how food security may relate to income and labor, proximity to markets, and prices. The data collected in Ghana complements a household and market survey recently completed by our colleagues at Indiana University and the Zambia Agriculture Research Institute in Lusaka.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Natasha Krell</name><email>nkrell@ucsb.edu</email></author><category term="2017" /><category term="Borlaug Fellow" /><category term="Ghana" /><category term="Zambia" /><category term="Award" /><category term="Cascade Tuholske" /><category term="Food Security" /><summary type="html">Cascade was named a Borlaug Fellow in Global Food Security to examine urban food security in Accra, Ghana and Lusaka, Zambia.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cynthia Gerlein-Safdi named to Michigan Society of Fellows</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/15/cynthia-michigan/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cynthia Gerlein-Safdi named to Michigan Society of Fellows" /><published>2017-05-15T19:01:00+03:00</published><updated>2017-05-15T19:01:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/15/cynthia-gerlein-safdi-named-to-michigan-society-of-fellows</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/15/cynthia-michigan/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Cynthia_michigan.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cynthia Gerlein-Safdi&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/people/gerlein-safdi/&quot;&gt;Cynthia Gerlein-Safdi&lt;/a&gt;, WAVES lab member and PhD student in Civil and Environmental Engineering at Princeton, was named a &lt;a href=&quot;https://record.umich.edu/articles/michigan-society-fellows-name-nine-new-members&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; Michigan Society Fellow &lt;/a&gt; for 2017. Fellows were chosen for the importance and quality of their scholarship and for their interest in interdisciplinary work. During Cynthia’s tenure at the University of Michigan, she will teach selected courses in her affiliated department - Climate and Space Sciences and Engineering - and continue her  research into the use of radar remotes sensing to characterize the patterns and dynamics of canopy water content. Congratulations, Cynthia!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kelly Caylor</name></author><category term="2017" /><category term="Michigan Society of Fellows" /><category term="Cynthia Gerlein-Safdo" /><category term="Remote Sensing" /><category term="Plant Water Use" /><summary type="html">Cynthia has been selected as one of nine new fellows out of 949 applications to serve three-year appointments as postdoctoral scholars and assistant professors, beginning this fall.</summary></entry></feed>